<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Generated by crowdin.com-->
<resources>
  <string name="about_privileges"><h2>Uživatelské role a jejich oprávnění</h2>
<h3>Vydavatel</h3>
<ul>
    <li>přidává, upravuje a odstraňuje články, odkazy a komentáře</li>
    <li>smí používat PHP v článcích, jestliže je v Nastavení volba ‚Používat PHP v článcích?‘ nastavena ‚Ano‘</li>
    <li>nahrává, upravuje a odstraňuje obrázky a soubory</li>
    <li>upravuje rubriky a kategorie</li>
    <li>upravuje stránky, formy a styly</li>
    <li>prohlíží diagnostické informace</li>
    <li>upravuje nastavení serveru</li>
    <li>přidává a odstraňuje uživatele a přiděluje jejich práva</li>
    <li>prohlíží záznamy o návštěvnících webu</li>
    <li>nahrává a upravuje pluginy</li>
    <li>může importovat data</li>
</ul>
<h3>Šéfredaktor</h3>
<ul>
    <li>přidává, upravuje a odstraňuje články, odkazy a komentáře</li>
    <li>smí používat PHP v článcích, jestliže je v Nastavení volba ‚Používat PHP v článcích?‘ nastavena ‚Ano‘</li>
    <li>nahrává, upravuje a odstraňuje obrázky a soubory</li>
    <li>upravuje rubriky a kategorie</li>
    <li>upravuje stránky, formy a styly</li>
    <li>prohlíží diagnostické informace</li>
    <li>upravuje nastavení serveru</li>
    <li>může prohlížet údaje o uživatelích</li>
    <li>prohlíží záznamy o návštěvnících webu</li>
    <li>nahrává a upravuje pluginy</li>
    <li>může importovat data</li>
</ul>
<h3>Redaktor</h3>
<ul>
    <li>přidává, upravuje a odstraňuje články s tímto omezením:
        <ul>
            <li>nemůže mazat články ostatních autorů</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>spravuje komentáře a odkazy</li>
    <li>spravuje obrázky a soubory</li>
    <li>upravuje rubriky a kategorie</li>
    <li>upravuje stránky a formy</li>
    <li>může prohlížet údaje uživatelů</li>
    <li>prohlíží záznamy o návštěvnících webu</li>
</ul>
<h3>Redakční autor</h3>
<ul>
    <li>vytváří, upravuje a odstraňuje vlastní články, smí prohlížet články ostatních autorů</li>
    <li>nahrává a upravuje vlastní obrázky a soubory</li>
</ul>
<h3>Přispěvatel</h3>
<ul>
    <li>přidává, upravuje a odstraňuje vlastní články s tímto omezením: 
        <ul>
            <li>upravovat článek může jen do chvíle jeho vydání</li>
            <li>článek ukládá <em>pouze</em> jako Návrh, Skrytý, nebo Čekající</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>může prohlížet články ostatních autorů</li>
</ul>
<h3>Návrhář</h3>
<ul>
    <li>přidává, upravuje a odstraňuje vlastní články s tímto omezením: 
        <ul>
            <li>upravovat článek může jen do chvíle jeho vydání</li>
            <li>článek ukládá <em>pouze</em> jako Návrh, Skrytý, nebo Čekající</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>může prohlížet články ostatních autorů</li>
    <li>spravuje obrázky</li>
    <li>spravuje rubriky</li>
    <li>upravuje stránky, formy a styly</li>
</ul></string>
  <string name="add_new_author"><h2>Uživatelé: Přidat nového autora</h2>
<p>Heslo, uvítací email a instrukce k přihlášení budou novému autorovi zaslány emailem.</p></string>
  <string name="admin_side_plugins"><h1>Nastavení: Pluginy pro administraci?</h1>
<p>Pluginy pro administraci mohou změnit fungování administrační části systému Textpattern a rozšířit ho o další funkce.</p>
<p>Chceš-li se o pluginech dozvědět více, podívej se na stránku <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/development/">Extending Textpattern</a>, která je součástí <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/">dokumentace Textpatternu</a>. pluginy všech druhů jsou shromážděny na <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://textpattern.org/">Textpattern Resources</a>.</p></string>
  <string name="remember_login"><h2>Zapamatovat přihlášení</h2>
<p>Je-li tato volba zatržena, zůstaneš v prohlížeči do Textpattern přihlášen(a), dokud se neodhlásíš. Pokud necháš pole nezatržené, dojde po určité době nečinnosti automaticky k odhlášení.</p>
<p>Vyžaduje, aby měl prohlížeč zapnuté cookies.</p></string>
  <string name="article_image"><h2>Psaní: Obrázek článku</h2>     
<p>Chceš-li k článku přiřadit jeden obrázek, zadej do tohoto pole z následujících možností:</p>     
<ol>              
  <li>ID obrázku - identifikační číslo obrázku na stránce Obsah/Obrázky</li>              
  <li>relativní URL cestu k obrázku (např. <code>/images/muj-obrazek.jpg</code>)</li>              
  <li>absolutní URL adresu obrázku (např. <code>http://example.com/cesta/do/images/muj-obrazek.jpg</code>)</li>     
</ol>     
<p>Obrázek bude v článku zobrazen pomocí tagu <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.i/tags/article_image">      <code>&lt;txp:article_image /&gt;</code><span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(otevřít odkaz v novém okně) </span></a> ve formě (šabloně) pro článek. Výstupem je HTML tag <code>&lt;img&gt;</code> vybraného obrázku.</p></string>
  <string name="body"><h2>Psaní: Tělo článku</h2>
<p>Hlavní obsah článku.</p>
<p>Během přípravy článku můžete v systému Textpattern přepínat mezi třemi způsoby jeho zobrazení: prostý text, text s HTML tagy (značkami, pomocí kterých prohlížeč vykreslí článek) a náhledem výsledku.</p></string>
  <string name="description"><h2>Psaní: Description</h2>
<p>Popis článku je volitelná součást, která může pomoci prohledávačůmwebových stránek lépe rozpoznávat a třídit obsah.</p>
<p>Popis článku je omezen na maximálně 255 znaků. Některé vyhledávače mohou mít i menší limit znaků pro <code>meta description</code> </p>
<p> Všimněte si, že popis článku se liší od anotace článku, ačkoli mohou mít podobný, nebo stejný obsah. Popis článku je primárně určen pro použití vyhledávačům a robotům, zatímco anotace článku slouží čtenářům jako stručné shrnutí obsahu článku. </p></string>
  <string name="excerpt"><h2>Psaní: Anotace</h2>
<p>Anotace článku není povinná. Zpravidla jde o krátké shrnutí obsahu článku, které se zobrazuje v seznamu článků, či obsahu serveru, nebo se používá namísto celého těla článku v pramenech RSS a Atom.</p></string>
  <string name="expire_date"><h2>Psaní: Datum expirace</h2>
<p>Datum, kdy článku vyprší platnost. Čas je volitelný a lze nastavit na libovolnou dobu v minulosti nebo budoucnosti.</p>
<p>Políčka jsou určené pro následující informace:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rok / Měsíc / Den</li>
    <li>Hodina (24-hodinový formát) : Minuta : Sekunda</li>
</ul>
<p>Je-li povolena možnost vydat expirované články, článek zůstává viditelný. V případě, že je možnost zobrazování prošlých článků zakázána, uvidí návštěvníci stránky namísto obsahu článku výpis Chyba HTTP 410.</p></string>
  <string name="keywords"><h2>Psaní: Klíčová slova</h2>
<p>Klíčová slova jsou užitečná pro určení vztahů mezi články, jiných než jen podle příslušnosti k téže kategorii.</p>
<p>Klíčová slova musejí být pouze samostatná slova, oddělená čárkami.</p></string>
  <string name="override_form"><h2>Psaní: Přebít formu</h2>
<p>V případě, že chceš pro určitý článek použít jinou formu než tu,která je určena jako výchozí, vyber ji zde. Jako příklad lze uvést situaci, kdy chceš místo celého <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/body"><code>&lt;txp:těla /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(otevřít odkaz v novém okně)</span></a> jednoho konkrétního článku, jak by se zobrazil normálně, použít pouze <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/excerpt"><code>&lt;txp:anotaci /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(otevřít odkaz v novém okně)</span></a>.</p></string>
  <string name="publish_date"><h2>Psaní: Datum vydání</h2>
<p>Čas publikování, nebo uložení poslední úpravy článku. Čas může být zadán jako okamžik, kdy je článek publikován, nebo na libovolnou dobu v minulosti nebo budoucnosti. </p>
<p>Políčka jsou určené pro následující informace:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rok / Měsíc / Den</li>
    <li>Hodina (24-hodinový formát) : Minuta : Sekunda</li>
</ul>
<p>Článek s datem vydání v budoucnosti nebude na úvodní straně ani v pramenech RSS / Atom zobrazen až do zadaného okamžiku. </p></string>
  <string name="title"><h2>Psaní. Název článku</h2>
<p>Stručný, vystižný název pro tento článek.</p>
<p>Délka názvu článku je omezena na maximálně 255 znaků.</p></string>
  <string name="url_title"><h2>Write: URL-only title</h2>
<p>Chceš-li do trvalého odkazu na článek vložit vlastní název, zadej jej zde. Necháš-li pole prázné, název do odkazu bude automaticky odvozen z názvu článku.</p>
<p>Používej malá písmena bez diakritiky, slova odděluj pomlčkami, nebo podtržítky.</p></string>
  <string name="article_category"><h2>Kategorie: Články</h2>
<p>Na rozdíl od rubrik, jež určují navigační strukturu serveru, slouží kategorie spíše k roztřídění článků podle tématu. Jsou-li články zařazeny do kategorí, lze procházet seznamy článků v jednotlivých kategoriích.</p>
<p>Příklady kategorií na stránkách o jídle:</p>
<ul>
    <li>suroviny</li>
    <li>nákupy</li>
    <li>recepty</li>
    <li>servírování</li>
    <li>restarurace</li>
    <li>šéfkuchaři</li>
</ul></string>
  <string name="category_description"><h2>Kategorie: Popis</h2> <p>Popis kategorie je volitelná část, která může pomoci vyhledávačům a robotům lépe určit a uspořádat obsah.</p> <p>Popis je omezen na maximálně 255 znaků. Některé vyhledávače mohou mít pro <code>meta description</code> nastaven jiný limit znaků kvůli praktičnosti stránky výsledků zobrazené internetovým vyhledávačem (SERPs), a ten může být menší než limit 255 znaků v Textpatternu.</p></string>
  <string name="file_category"><h2>Kategorie: Soubory</h2>
<p>Volitelná možnost. Kategorie souborů ti umožní snažší správu a seskupování nahraných souborů.</p></string>
  <string name="image_category"><h2>Kategorie: Obrázky</h2>
<p>Kategorie obrázků jsou užitečné jak pro organizaci obrázků, tak pro určení skupin obrázků, jež lze podle kategorie zobrazit najednou pomocí značek <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/image_index"><code>&lt;txp:image_index /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(odkaz se otevře v novém okně)</span></a> a <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/image_display"><code>&lt;txp:image_display /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(odkaz se otevře v novém okně)</span></a></p></string>
  <string name="link_category"><h2>Kategorie: Odkazy</h2>
<p>Volitelná možnost. Kategorie odkazů jsou užitečné pro členění odkazů  do skupin, např. „Přátelé”, „Římané”, „Krajané”, atd.</p>
<p>Vybraný seznam odkazů lze zobrazit pomocí tagu <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/linklist"><code>&lt;txp:linklist /&gt;</code><span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(otevře odkaz v novém okně)</span></a> např. takto:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;code&gt;&lt;txp:linklist category="pratele" /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.</code></pre></string>
  <string name="clean_url_data_failed"><h2>Diagnostics: Clean URL data failed</h2>
<p>It appears that either your site URLs (<code>http://example.com/section/article</code>) are currently not working or your server does not support the test procedure to determine if clean URLs work or not; if clean URLs on your site work, you can safely ignore this message.</p>
<p>If clean URLs are <em>not</em> working it may mean either:</p>
<ul>
    <li>your ‘Site URL’ setting is incorrect, or the page at that address is not managed by this copy of Textpattern.</li>
    <li>your server requires some changes to <code>.htaccess</code> in order to make clean URLs work.</li>
    <li>your server doesn’t support clean URLs at all.</li>
</ul>
<p>The clean URL test attempts to fetch a page from the web address specified in the ‘Site URL’ preference in order to check that all clean URL parameters are working correctly. If that URL is a different site, or has been replaced with a static page or similar, the test will fail. Until the issue is resolved you will have to use messy URLs on your site instead (<code>http://example.com?s=section&amp;id=4</code>). Ensure the ‘Permanent link mode’ in Admin Preferences is set accordingly.</p>
<p>Note that using a plugin to put a site in ‘maintenance mode’ may trigger this warning.</p></string>
  <string name="clean_url_test_failed"><h2>Diagnostics: Clean URL test failed</h2>
<p>It appears that either your site URLs (<code>http://example.com/section/article</code>) are currently not working or your server does not support the test procedure to determine if clean URLs work or not; if clean URLs on your site work, you can safely ignore this message.</p>
<p>If clean URLs are not working it may mean either:</p>
<ul>
    <li>your ‘Site URL’ setting is incorrect, or the page at that address is not managed by this copy of Textpattern</li>
    <li>your server requires some changes to <code>.htaccess</code> in order to make clean URLs work</li>
    <li>your server doesn’t support clean URLs at all</li>
</ul>
<p>The clean URL test attempts to fetch a page from the web address specified in the ‘Site URL’ preference in order to check that all clean URL parameters are working correctly. If that URL is a different site, or has been replaced with a static page or similar, the test will fail. Until the issue is resolved you will have to use messy URLs on your site instead (<code>http://example.com?s=section&amp;id=4</code>). Ensure the ‘Permanent link mode’ in Admin Preferences is set accordingly.</p></string>
  <string name="cleanurl_only_apache"><h2>Diagnostics: Clean URL support</h2>
<p>Clean URLs are only supported on Apache. If you are using another server platform, use short URLs at your own risk.</p></string>
  <string name="dev_version_live"><h2>Diagnostics: Development code on a live server</h2>
<p>You are running in-development files on a live production site which is not recommended. If you know this already and are happy to do so, you may ignore this warning.</p></string>
  <string name="dir_not_writable"><h2>Diagnostics: Directory is not writable</h2>
<p>To use the file and image upload capabilities, these directories have to be writable by PHP. Usually this means you have to change permissions so the web server user has write access to the directory. This can be done with your FTP client, or alternatively on the command line by issuing a <code>chmod 755 /path/to/dir</code> command.</p></string>
  <string name="dns_lookup_fails"><h2>Diagnostics: DNS fails</h2>
<p>It appears the URL you specified as the address of your site is unreachable.</p></string>
  <string name="file_uploads_disabled"><h2>Diagnostics: File uploads are disabled</h2>
<p>Your current server configuration shows that file uploads are disabled so you will not be able to upload using Textpattern’s ‘Files’ and/or ‘Images’ panel. Please check and alter the <code>file_uploads</code> setting in <code>php.ini</code> (or ask your host to alter it).</p></string>
  <string name="htaccess_missing"><h2>Diagnostics: .htaccess file missing</h2>
<p>You are using a permanent link mode which requires an <code>.htaccess</code> file to be placed in your site root directory. The recommended directives are:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;IfModule mod_rewrite.c&gt;
    RewriteEngine On
    #RewriteBase /relative/web/path/
    RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME} -f [OR]
    RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME} -d
    RewriteRule ^(.+) - [PT,L]
    RewriteCond %{REQUEST_URI} !=/favicon.ico
    RewriteRule ^(.*) index.php
    RewriteCond %{HTTP:Authorization}  !^$
    RewriteRule .* - [E=REMOTE_USER:%{HTTP:Authorization}]
&lt;/IfModule&gt;</code></pre></string>
  <string name="index_inaccessible"><h2>Diagnostics: Site index inaccessible</h2>
<p>The main <code>index.php</code> file specified as the index for your site is unreadable by the server. Please check permissions.</p></string>
  <string name="missing_files"><h2>Diagnostics: Missing files</h2>
<p>Some essential files are missing from your Textpattern installation. Ensure that all the listed files are present on your server and are in the correct locations.</p></string>
  <string name="mod_rewrite_missing"><h2>Diagnostics: Apache mod_rewrite missing</h2>
<p>Apache’s <code>mod_rewrite</code> module is not installed, or installed but not enabled. This is recommended for Textpattern to function correctly. Please check your <code>.htaccess</code> file is set up correctly, or contact your host for assistance.</p></string>
  <string name="modified_files"><h2>Diagnostics: Modified files</h2>
<p>Files are determined to be modified if their respective checksum differs from the known-good checksum list. If any files in the Textpattern installation are different to those expected, the files will be highlighted here. This is not necessarily a problem, but may be worth checking out if you are having problems with the functionality of your site.</p></string>
  <string name="mysql_table_errors"><h2>Diagnostics: MySQL table errors</h2>
<p>Something is probably corrupt or otherwise damaged in your MySQL database. If you have access to a MySQL access tool, such as <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://www.phpmyadmin.net">phpMyAdmin <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a>, try repairing the affected table(s).</p></string>
  <string name="no_temp_dir"><h2>Diagnostics: No temp directory defined</h2>
<p>While Textpattern will run without a temporary directory, some functionality may not work as expected if this preference is not set. Please visit Admin Preferences and set up the ‘Temporary directory path’.</p></string>
  <string name="old_files"><h2>Diagnostics: Old files</h2>
<p>Some Textpattern files are out-of-date and should be replaced with the latest versions from the relevant stable release.</p></string>
  <string name="old_placeholder_exists"><h2>Diagnostics: Section placeholder file exists</h2>
<p>As of Textpattern version 4.0, section placeholder files are no longer required, and will conflict with the the new <code>.htaccess</code> scheme. If the reported files are placeholders, please delete them.</p></string>
  <string name="path_not_doc_root"><h2>Diagnostics: path_to_site does not match</h2>
<p>Two variables set by your web server which should match, but do not.</p></string>
  <string name="path_to_site_inacc"><h2>Diagnostics: Site directory unreadable</h2>
<p>The directory containing the <code>index.php</code> file specified as the index for your site is unreadable by the server. Please check permissions.</p></string>
  <string name="php_version_required"><h2>Diagnostics: Minimum version requirements</h2>
<p>Textpattern requires certain functionality present in the PHP programming language and MySQL database server. Please consult the following table to determine the minimum system requirements for the version of Textpattern you have downloaded:</p>
<div class="txp-listtables">
    <table class="txp-list">
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th scope="col">Textpattern version</th>
                <th scope="col">Minimum PHP version</th>
                <th scope="col">Minimum MySQL version</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <th scope="row">4.6.x</th>
                <td>5.3.3</td>
                <td>4.1</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <th scope="row">4.5.x</th>
                <td>5.2.3</td>
                <td>4.1</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <th scope="row">4.0.1 - 4.4.1</th>
                <td>4.3</td>
                <td>3.23</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
</div>
<p>In addition to the above system requirements, the following PHP extensions are required:</p>
<ul>
    <li><a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/ref.mysql.php">MySQL <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a></li>
    <li><a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/ref.xml.php">XML <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a></li>
    <li><a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/ref.json.php">JSON <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p>Your <code>php.ini</code> file, either global or local, should contain a <code>date.timezone</code> setting.</p></string>
  <string name="setup_still_exists"><h2>Diagnostics: \'setup\' directory still exists</h2>
<p>When Textpattern has been installed, the <code>textpattern/setup</code> directory and its contents are no longer needed and should be deleted. You will continue to receive this warning until it has been removed, as this can potentially be a security concern.</p></string>
  <string name="site_url_mismatch"><h2>Diagnostics: Site URL mismatch</h2>
<p>The Site URL as set in the ‘Preferences’ administration panel does not match the actual URL you use to visit your website.</p>
<p>If your website can be reached through multiple different URLs, or if the links on your Textpattern powered website all function correctly, you can safely ignore this warning.</p>
<p>Otherwise, you are advised to correct the ‘Site URL’ setting in Admin Preferences. An educated guess of the correct Site URL is shown in the pre-flight warning message on the ‘Diagnostics’ administration panel.</p></string>
  <string name="some_php_functions_disabled"><h2>Diagnostics: The following PHP functions: [&#8230;] are disabled on your server</h2>
<p>This means your hosting company or server administrator has disabled one or more PHP functions, some of which may affect the running of Textpattern.</p>
<p>Please consult the <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/administration/diagnostics-panel">Textpattern User Documentation <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> for further information.</p></string>
  <string name="textpattern_version_update"><h2>Diagnostics: Textpattern CMS version update</h2>
<p>There is a newer version of Textpattern CMS available. To take advantage of the latest features and security, it is recommended you upgrade.</p>
<p>Please note that while we strive to make the upgrade experience as seamless and pain-free as possible:</p>
<ul>
    <li>If only the last digit differs from your current version, the upgrade is likely to be backwards compatible with plugins and themes.</li>
    <li>If the last two digits differ from your current version, the upgrade might require updates to some plugins and/or themes, although it will probably continue to work anyway in a limited capacity.</li>
    <li>If the first digit is different from your current version, the upgrade is likely to require updates to most plugins and themes. If you rely heavily on a particular plugin or theme feature, please check with the author or community members before commencing the upgrade.</li>
</ul>
<p>If the messages reads “There is a problem trying to connect to the RPC server” it means a new version could not be checked at this time, or the server may be down. Updates are checked for every 24 hours so it is likely that next time you visit the Diagnostics panel, all will be well.</p></string>
  <string name="tmp_plugin_paths_match"><h2>Diagnostics: Temporary directory path and Plugin cache directory path should not match</h2>
<p>Plugins should have their own directory and not share the temporary directory. This is a potential security risk and may adversely affect your site if the temporary directory is flushed. Please ensure that the temporary directory path is different to the plugin cache path.</p></string>
  <string name="update_still_exists"><h2>Diagnostics: \'update\' directory still exists</h2>
<p>When Textpattern has been upgraded, the <code>textpattern/update</code> directory and its contents are no longer needed and recommended for deletion. You will continue to receive this warning until it has been removed.</p></string>
  <string name="warn_mail_unavailable"><h2>Diagnostics: Your PHP installation is missing the mail() function</h2>
<p>PHP’s <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/function.mail.php">mail <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> function is disabled. Therefore, Textpattern cannot send emails and some functionality will not be available. For example, email notifications for new comments will not be sent, and new users will not receive a welcome email. Users can still be added, however.</p></string>
  <string name="warn_register_globals_or_update"><h2>Diagnostics: Turn register_globals off or update to a newer PHP version</h2>
<p>A severe vulnerability was discovered in certain versions of PHP concerning the controversial legacy feature <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/security.globals.php">registered globals <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a>. This can lead to unexpected behaviour of PHP applications, which can potentially allow execution of remote PHP code in many situations.</p>
<p>Vulnerable versions are PHP4 versions &lt;= 4.4.0 and PHP5 versions &lt;= 5.0.5. You should either update to a newer version or make sure that <code>register_globals</code> is turned off. <code>register_globals</code> was deprecated as of PHP 5.3.0 and removed as of PHP 5.4.0.</p>
<p>You can turn off <code>register_globals</code> in the <code>php.ini</code> file. If you are in a hosted environment, you may have an option in your hosting control panel for it (ask your host). When running PHP as an Apache module, it is also possible to turn <code>register_globals</code> off via Apache’s <code>.htaccess</code> configuration files. Uncomment the following line from your <code>.htaccess</code> file by removing the leading #:</p>
<pre><code>php_value register_globals 0</code></pre></string>
  <string name="file_reassign"><h2>Files: Reassign file</h2>
<p>When you upload a file in place of one that is labelled ‘Missing’, your chosen file is uploaded to the server and linked to the original file information in the database. This means the file name of the original file will remain, as will all other associated information such as download count and category. The file size will, however, be updated to reflect the new file.</p></string>
  <string name="file_replace"><h2>Files: Replace file</h2>
<p>Uploading a file here will replace the contents of the existing file on the server but will keep the file name the same as it was before. The download count and other information associated with the file remain unaffected.</p></string>
  <string name="upload"><h2>Files: Upload file</h2>
<p>Use this form to upload files or images to your server.</p>
<p>Use the Textile code to render graphics within articles, the Textpattern code to place graphics on your page templates, or HTML code to place the graphics elsewhere.</p></string>
  <string name="forms_overview"><h2>Forms: Introduction</h2>
<p>In Textpattern, a form is a snippet or chunk of text, HTML, and Textpattern tags that can be reused to display content.</p>
<p>Here’s an example form which could be named <code>ordinary_list</code>:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;txp:permlink&gt;
        &lt;txp:title /&gt;
    &lt;/txp:permlink&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;</code></pre>
<p>You could use it to display an HTML unordered list of related articles:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;txp:related_articles form="ordinary_list" wraptag="ul" /&gt;</code></pre>
<p>Since the role of this form is to output a list of titles, it could be applicable inside other tags, such as showing 20 articles from the current section:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;txp:article form="ordinary_list" limit="20" wraptag="ol" /&gt;</code></pre>
<p>You may also choose to employ a form to display repeated content, such as header and footer in your page templates. This means the content only exists in one place and if you decide to change it, you only need to do it once. Displaying content from a form is usually accomplished with:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;txp:output_form form="your_form_name" /&gt;</code></pre>
<p>A form can be up to 64KB in size. An example for a footer might include headings, paragraphs, links, conditional tags, and references to other forms such as <code>ordinary_list</code>.</p></string>
  <string name="create_thumbnail"><h2>Images: Create thumbnail</h2>
<p>Allows you to (re)create a thumbnail of the specified dimensions from the full size image.</p>
<p>The thumbnail will be scaled to fit the dimensions you choose, unless you select the ‘Crop’ checkbox. In that case, the thumbnail will be created from the centre of the image without any scaling.</p></string>
  <string name="replace_image_form"><h2>Images: Replace image</h2>
<p>An image uploaded here will simply replace the existing one associated with this entry in the database.</p></string>
  <string name="upload_image"><h2>Images: Upload image</h2>
<p>Upload one or more images to your server.</p>
<p>Upon upload to the <code>images</code> directory, the filename of your original image will be kept only internally in Textpattern’s database; the image file itself will be renamed to a sequential number + file extension.</p></string>
  <string name="upload_thumbnail"><h2>Images: Upload thumbnail</h2>
<p>Full size images can be assigned their own thumbnails. These are useful for linking to - and the indexing of - full size images.</p>
<p>A reference to the thumbnail is exactly the same as the reference to the full size image, with <code>t</code> appended to the file name. For example, to reference a thumbnail associated with a full size image stored at <code>/images/12.jpg</code> you would use <code>/images/12t.jpg</code>.</p></string>
</resources>
