<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Generated by crowdin.com-->
<resources>
  <string name="about_privileges"><h1>Användare: Olika roller</h1>
<h3>Utgivare</h3>
<ul>
    <li>kan hantera artiklar, kommentarer och länkar</li>
    <li>kan använda PHP i artiklar om administratörsinställningarna ‘Tillåter PHP i artiklarna?’ är satt till ‘Ja’</li>
    <li>kan hantera bilder och filer</li>
    <li>kan hantera sektioner och kategorier</li>
    <li>kan hantera sidor, former och stilar</li>
    <li>kan se på diagnostikinformation</li>
    <li>kan hantera webbplatsens inställningar</li>
    <li>kan hantera användare</li>
    <li>kan hantera besöksloggarna</li>
    <li>kan hantera tillägg</li>
    <li>kan importera data</li>
</ul>
<h3>Redaktionschef</h3>
<ul>
    <li>kan hantera artiklar, kommentarer och länkar</li>
    <li>kan använda PHP i artiklar om administratörsinställningarna ‘Tillåter PHP i artiklarna?’ är satt till ‘Ja’</li>
    <li>kan hantera bilder och filer</li>
    <li>kan hantera sektioner och kategorier</li>
    <li>kan hantera sidor, former och stilar</li>
    <li>kan se på diagnostikinformation</li>
    <li>kan hantera webbplatsens inställningar</li>
    <li>kan se på användare</li>
    <li>kan hantera besöksloggarna</li>
    <li>kan hantera tillägg</li>
    <li>kan importera data</li>
</ul>
<h3>Redaktör</h3>
<ul>
    <li>kan hantera artiklar med en begränsning:
    <ul>
        <li>kan inte ta bort det som tillhör andra användare</li>
    </ul></li>
    <li>kan hantera kommentarer och länkar</li>
    <li>kan hantera bilder och filer</li>
    <li>kan hantera kategorier</li>
    <li>kan hantera sidor och former</li>
    <li>kan se på användare</li>
    <li>kan hantera besöksloggarna</li>
</ul>
<h3>Redaktionsmedarbetare</h3>
<ul>
    <li>kan hantera egna artiklar, se på andra användares artiklar</li>
    <li>kan hantera bilder och filer</li>
</ul>
<h3>Frilansare</h3>
<ul>
    <li>kan hantera sina egna artiklar med vissa begränsningar:
    <ul>
        <li>kan endast ändra artiklar fram till de blir publicerade</li>
        <li>kan verkställa statusen <em>endast</em> på Utkast, Gömd eller Påseende</li>
    </ul></li>
    <li>se på andra användares artiklar</li>
</ul>
<h3>Formgivare</h3>
<ul>
    <li>kan hantera sina egna artiklar med vissa begränsningar:
    <ul>
        <li>kan endast ändra artiklar fram till de blir publicerade</li>
        <li>kan verkställa statusen <em>endast</em> på Utkast, Gömd eller Påseende</li>
    </ul></li>
    <li>se på andra användares artiklar</li>
    <li>kan hantera bilder</li>
    <li>kan hantera sektioner</li>
    <li>kan hantera sidor, former och stilar</li>
</ul></string>
  <string name="add_new_author"><h2>Användare: Lägg till ny författare</h2>
<p>Ett lösenord, välkomstmeddelande och instruktioner om hur du loggar in kommer att e-postas till den nye författaren.</p></string>
  <string name="admin_side_plugins"><h1>Inställningar: Använd administratörs-sidtillägg?</h1>
<p>Administratörs-sidtillägg kan ändra funktionen av administrationsgränssnittet. De kan koppla in redan befintliga åtgärder, som redigering eller publicering av artiklar, eller de kan lägga till nya paneler för extra/utökad funktionalitet.</p>
<p>Om du vill lära dig mer om administratörs-sidtillägg, ta då en titt på <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/development/">Extending Textpattern</a> sida i <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/">Textpattern User Documentation</a>. Alla sorters tillägg finns listade på <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://textpattern.org/">Textpattern Resources</a> webbplatsen.</p></string>
  <string name="remember_login"><h2>Kom ihåg inloggning</h2>
<p>Markerad kommer du att vara inloggad på ditt Textpattern-konto med nuvarande webbläsare, tills du väljer att logga ut. Om du låter den vara avmarkerad, kommer du att bli automatiskt utloggad efter en tid av inaktivitet.</p>
<p>Kräver att cookies är aktiverat i din webbläsare.</p></string>
  <string name="article_image"><h2>Skriva: Artikelbild</h2>
<p>Om du vill inkludera en bild med denna artikel, ange en av följande här:</p>
<ol>
    <li>en Textpattern bild-ID</li>
    <li>en relativ URL till bilden (t.ex <code>/images/my_pic.jpg</code>)</li>
    <li>en fullständiga URL (t.ex <code>http://example.com/path/to/images/my_pic.jpg</code>)</li>
</ol>
<p>Bilden kan visas genom att placera en <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/article_image"><code>&lt;txp:article_image /&gt;</code> tagg <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(öppnar extern länk i ett nytt fönster)</span></a> i en artikelform. Den kommer att visa en fullständig HTML <code>&lt;img&gt;</code>-tagg till den valda bilden.</p></string>
  <string name="body"><h2>Skriv: Brödtext</h2>
<p>Det huvudsakliga innehållet i en artikel finns i artiklens brödtext.</p>
<p>När du skriver eller förbereda artiklar för publicering i Textpattern, du kan växla mellan tre vyer av artikeln: oformatterad text, HTML-kod (koden med vilken en webbläsare skapar artikeln), och en renderade förhandsvisning.</p></string>
  <string name="description"><h2>Skriv: Beskrivning</h2>
<p>Artikelbeskrivningen är en valfri komponent som kan hjälpa sökmotorer och sökrobotar att bättre identifiera och sortera innehåll.</p>
<p>Artikelbeskrivningen är begränsad till maximalt 255 tecken. Observera att vissa sökmotorer sätter teckenbegränsningen efter längden på en sidas <code>meta-beskriving</code> för praktisk visning på sökmotorns resultatsida (SERPs) och detta kan vara mindre än de 255 tecken som Textpattern har.</p>
<p>Observera att artikelbeskrivningen skiljer sig från artikelutdraget, även om de båda accepterar liknande innehåll. Artikelbeskrivning bör i första hand vara avsedd för sökmotorer och sökrobotar, medan artikelutdraget är mer lämpad för en artikelsammanfattning läsbar när så önskas.</p></string>
  <string name="excerpt"><h2>Write: Utdrag</h2>
<p>Artikelutdrag är valfria. Utdrag ska användas som en kort sammanfattning av artikeln som visas som en del av en innehållsförteckning, som används i stället för hela artikelbrödtexten i webbplatsens RSS-/Atom-flöden, eller ett antal andra användningsområden.</p></string>
  <string name="expire_date"><h2>Skriva: Utgångsdatum</h2>
<p>Tiden en artikel är märkt som utgången. Tiden är frivilligt och kan ställas in på en godtycklig tid i det förflutna eller framåt i tiden.</p>
<p>Rutorna innehåller följande information:</p>
<ul>
    <li>År / Månad / Dag</li>
    <li>Timmar (24-timmarsformat) : Minut : Sekund</li>
</ul>
<p>När tiden inträffar, eller om en tid som redan varit anges, kommer artikeln att utgå.</p>
<p>Om alternativet att visa utgångna artiklar är aktiverat förblir artikeln synlig. Om alternativet att visa utgångna artiklar inaktiveras kommer besökare till artikelsidan få ett HTTP 410-fel i stället för artikelns innehåll.</p></string>
  <string name="keywords"><h2>Write: Nyckelord</h2>
<p>Nyckelord är användbara till att förfina sambanden mellan artiklar utöver de som tillhandahålls av kategorierna.</p>
<p>Nyckelord måste vara enskilda ord separerade med kommatecken.</p></string>
  <string name="override_form"><h2>Skriv: Åsidosätt formulär</h2>
<p>Om du önskar att en artikel ska använda en form som skiljer sig från den som ges som standard - till exempel om du vill visa endast ett artikelutdrag med <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/excerpt"><code>&lt;txp:excerpt /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(öppnar extern länk i ett nytt fönster)</span></a> där du normalt visar hela artikeln med <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/body"><code>&lt;txp:body /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(öppnar extern länk i ett nytt fönster)</span></a> - detta kan göras här.</p></string>
  <string name="publish_date"><h2>Write: Publiceringdatum</h2>
<p>The time an article or file is published or most-recently revised. The time can be set to the moment the item is published, or to an arbitrary time in the past or future.</p>
<p>The boxes correspond to the following information:</p>
<ul>
    <li>År / Månad / Dag</li>
    <li>Timmar (24-timmarsformat) : Minut : Sekund</li>
</ul>
<p>Ett objekt med en tidsstämpel som är större än den aktuella tiden (d.v.s. i framtiden) kommer inte att synas på förstasidan eller i RSS-/Atom-flödet tills den tiden kommer.</p></string>
  <string name="title"><h2>Skriv: Rubrik</h2>
<p>Skapa en lämplig rubrik för den här artikeln.</p>
<p>Artikelns rubrik är begränsad till maximalt 255 tecken.</p></string>
  <string name="url_title"><h2>Skriv: URL-rubrik</h2>
<p>Om du vill ha en särskild rubrik fäst till permanent URL för din artikel, ange den här. Om den lämnas tom, kommer URL-rubriken att automatiskt skapas från artikelns rubrik.</p>
<p>Detta är särskilt användbart om rubriken på din artikel använder icke-ASCII-tecken.</p></string>
  <string name="article_category"><h2>Categories: Articles</h2>
<p>Unlike sections, which define the navigational structure of a site, article categories allow organization of articles by their subject matter. Once categories are assigned, lists of articles belonging to particular categories can be browsed.</p>
<p>For example, likely article categories on a site about food might be:</p>
<ul>
    <li>raw ingredients</li>
    <li>shopping</li>
    <li>recipes</li>
    <li>presentation</li>
    <li>restaurants</li>
    <li>chefs</li>
</ul></string>
  <string name="category_description"><h2>Categories: Description</h2>
<p>The category description is an optional component that can help search engines and website crawlers better identify and sort content.</p>
<p>The category description is limited to a maximum of 255 characters. Note that some search engines place character limits on the length of a page’s <code>meta description</code> for practicality of display in search engine results pages (SERPs) and this may be less than the 255 character limit in Textpattern.</p></string>
  <string name="file_category"><h2>Kategorier: Filer</h2>
<p>Filkategorier är valfritt och är användbart om du vill gruppera vissa uppladdade filer tillsammans.</p></string>
  <string name="image_category"><h2>Categories: Images</h2>
<p>Image categories are useful both for internal organization, and for defining image sets that can be displayed using the <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/image_index"><code>&lt;txp:image_index /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> and <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/image_display"><code>&lt;txp:image_display /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> tags.</p></string>
  <string name="link_category"><h2>Categories: Links</h2>
<p>Link categories are optional, and are useful if you want to display different groupings of links, e.g. ‘Friends’, ‘Romans’, ‘Countrymen’.</p>
<p>Selective link lists such as these are output with the <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/linklist"><code>&lt;txp:linklist /&gt;</code> tag <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> like so:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;code&gt;&lt;txp:linklist category="Friends" /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.</code></pre></string>
  <string name="clean_url_data_failed"><h2>Diagnostics: Clean URL data failed</h2>
<p>It appears that either your site URLs (<code>http://example.com/section/article</code>) are currently not working or your server does not support the test procedure to determine if clean URLs work or not; if clean URLs on your site work, you can safely ignore this message.</p>
<p>If clean URLs are <em>not</em> working it may mean either:</p>
<ul>
    <li>your ‘Site URL’ setting is incorrect, or the page at that address is not managed by this copy of Textpattern.</li>
    <li>your server requires some changes to <code>.htaccess</code> in order to make clean URLs work.</li>
    <li>your server doesn’t support clean URLs at all.</li>
</ul>
<p>The clean URL test attempts to fetch a page from the web address specified in the ‘Site URL’ preference in order to check that all clean URL parameters are working correctly. If that URL is a different site, or has been replaced with a static page or similar, the test will fail. Until the issue is resolved you will have to use messy URLs on your site instead (<code>http://example.com?s=section&amp;id=4</code>). Ensure the ‘Permanent link mode’ in Admin Preferences is set accordingly.</p>
<p>Note that using a plugin to put a site in ‘maintenance mode’ may trigger this warning.</p></string>
  <string name="clean_url_test_failed"><h2>Diagnostics: Clean URL test failed</h2>
<p>It appears that either your site URLs (<code>http://example.com/section/article</code>) are currently not working or your server does not support the test procedure to determine if clean URLs work or not; if clean URLs on your site work, you can safely ignore this message.</p>
<p>If clean URLs are not working it may mean either:</p>
<ul>
    <li>your ‘Site URL’ setting is incorrect, or the page at that address is not managed by this copy of Textpattern</li>
    <li>your server requires some changes to <code>.htaccess</code> in order to make clean URLs work</li>
    <li>your server doesn’t support clean URLs at all</li>
</ul>
<p>The clean URL test attempts to fetch a page from the web address specified in the ‘Site URL’ preference in order to check that all clean URL parameters are working correctly. If that URL is a different site, or has been replaced with a static page or similar, the test will fail. Until the issue is resolved you will have to use messy URLs on your site instead (<code>http://example.com?s=section&amp;id=4</code>). Ensure the ‘Permanent link mode’ in Admin Preferences is set accordingly.</p></string>
  <string name="cleanurl_only_apache"><h2>Diagnostik: Clean URL support</h2>
<p>Det är endast Apache som stöder rena URL:er. Om du använder en annan serverplattform, använd korta URL: er på egen risk.</p></string>
  <string name="dev_version_live"><h2>Diagnostics: Development code on a live server</h2>
<p>You are running in-development files on a live production site which is not recommended. If you know this already and are happy to do so, you may ignore this warning.</p></string>
  <string name="dir_not_writable"><h2>Diagnostics: Directory is not writable</h2>
<p>To use the file and image upload capabilities, these directories have to be writable by PHP. Usually this means you have to change permissions so the web server user has write access to the directory. This can be done with your FTP client, or alternatively on the command line by issuing a <code>chmod 755 /path/to/dir</code> command.</p></string>
  <string name="dns_lookup_fails"><h2>Diagnostik: DNS-fel</h2>
<p>Det verkar som om URL:en du angav till din webbplats inte är tillgänglig.</p></string>
  <string name="file_uploads_disabled"><h2>Diagnostics: File uploads are disabled</h2>
<p>Your current server configuration shows that file uploads are disabled so you will not be able to upload using Textpattern’s ‘Files’ and/or ‘Images’ panel. Please check and alter the <code>file_uploads</code> setting in <code>php.ini</code> (or ask your host to alter it).</p></string>
  <string name="htaccess_missing"><h2>Diagnostik: filen .htaccess saknas</h2>
<p>Du använder ett permanent länkläge som kräver en <code>.htaccess</code>-fil som ska placeras i rotkatalogen på din webbplats. De rekommenderade direktiven är:</p>
<pre><code>&lt;IfModule mod_rewrite.c&gt;
    RewriteEngine On
    #RewriteBase /relative/web/path/
    RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME} -f [OR]
    RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME} -d
    RewriteRule ^(.+) - [PT,L]
    RewriteCond %{REQUEST_URI} !=/favicon.ico
    RewriteRule ^(.*) index.php
    RewriteCond %{HTTP:Authorization}  !^$
    RewriteRule .* - [E=REMOTE_USER:%{HTTP:Authorization}]
&lt;/IfModule&gt;</code></pre></string>
  <string name="index_inaccessible"><h2>Diagnostics: Site index inaccessible</h2>
<p>The main <code>index.php</code> file specified as the index for your site is unreadable by the server. Please check permissions.</p></string>
  <string name="missing_files"><h2>Diagnostics: Missing files</h2>
<p>Some essential files are missing from your Textpattern installation. Ensure that all the listed files are present on your server and are in the correct locations.</p></string>
  <string name="mod_rewrite_missing"><h2>Diagnostics: Apache mod_rewrite missing</h2>
<p>Apache’s <code>mod_rewrite</code> module is not installed, or installed but not enabled. This is recommended for Textpattern to function correctly. Please check your <code>.htaccess</code> file is set up correctly, or contact your host for assistance.</p></string>
  <string name="modified_files"><h2>Diagnostics: Modified files</h2>
<p>Files are determined to be modified if their respective checksum differs from the known-good checksum list. If any files in the Textpattern installation are different to those expected, the files will be highlighted here. This is not necessarily a problem, but may be worth checking out if you are having problems with the functionality of your site.</p></string>
  <string name="mysql_table_errors"><h2>Diagnostics: MySQL table errors</h2>
<p>Something is probably corrupt or otherwise damaged in your MySQL database. If you have access to a MySQL access tool, such as <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://www.phpmyadmin.net">phpMyAdmin <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a>, try repairing the affected table(s).</p></string>
  <string name="no_temp_dir"><h2>Diagnostics: No temp directory defined</h2>
<p>While Textpattern will run without a temporary directory, some functionality may not work as expected if this preference is not set. Please visit Admin Preferences and set up the ‘Temporary directory path’.</p></string>
  <string name="old_files"><h2>Diagnostics: Old files</h2>
<p>Some Textpattern files are out-of-date and should be replaced with the latest versions from the relevant stable release.</p></string>
  <string name="old_placeholder_exists"><h2>Diagnostics: Section placeholder file exists</h2>
<p>As of Textpattern version 4.0, section placeholder files are no longer required, and will conflict with the the new <code>.htaccess</code> scheme. If the reported files are placeholders, please delete them.</p></string>
  <string name="path_not_doc_root"><h2>Diagnostics: path_to_site does not match</h2>
<p>Two variables set by your web server which should match, but do not.</p></string>
  <string name="path_to_site_inacc"><h2>Diagnostics: Site directory unreadable</h2>
<p>The directory containing the <code>index.php</code> file specified as the index for your site is unreadable by the server. Please check permissions.</p></string>
  <string name="php_version_required"><h2>Diagnostics: Minimum version requirements</h2>
<p>Textpattern requires certain functionality present in the PHP programming language and MySQL database server. Please consult the following table to determine the minimum system requirements for the version of Textpattern you have downloaded:</p>
<div class="txp-listtables">
    <table class="txp-list">
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th scope="col">Textpattern version</th>
                <th scope="col">Minimum PHP version</th>
                <th scope="col">Minimum MySQL version</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <th scope="row">4.6.x</th>
                <td>5.3.3</td>
                <td>4.1</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <th scope="row">4.5.x</th>
                <td>5.2.3</td>
                <td>4.1</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <th scope="row">4.0.1 - 4.4.1</th>
                <td>4.3</td>
                <td>3.23</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
</div>
<p>In addition to the above system requirements, the following PHP extensions are required:</p>
<ul>
    <li><a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/ref.mysql.php">MySQL <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a></li>
    <li><a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/ref.xml.php">XML <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a></li>
    <li><a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/ref.json.php">JSON <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p>Your <code>php.ini</code> file, either global or local, should contain a <code>date.timezone</code> setting.</p></string>
  <string name="setup_still_exists"><h2>Diagnostics: \'setup\' directory still exists</h2>
<p>When Textpattern has been installed, the <code>textpattern/setup</code> directory and its contents are no longer needed and should be deleted. You will continue to receive this warning until it has been removed, as this can potentially be a security concern.</p></string>
  <string name="site_url_mismatch"><h2>Diagnostics: Site URL mismatch</h2>
<p>The Site URL as set in the ‘Preferences’ administration panel does not match the actual URL you use to visit your website.</p>
<p>If your website can be reached through multiple different URLs, or if the links on your Textpattern powered website all function correctly, you can safely ignore this warning.</p>
<p>Otherwise, you are advised to correct the ‘Site URL’ setting in Admin Preferences. An educated guess of the correct Site URL is shown in the pre-flight warning message on the ‘Diagnostics’ administration panel.</p></string>
  <string name="some_php_functions_disabled"><h2>Diagnostics: The following PHP functions: [&#8230;] are disabled on your server</h2>
<p>This means your hosting company or server administrator has disabled one or more PHP functions, some of which may affect the running of Textpattern.</p>
<p>Please consult the <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/administration/diagnostics-panel">Textpattern User Documentation <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> for further information.</p></string>
  <string name="textpattern_version_update"><h2>Diagnostics: Textpattern CMS version update</h2>
<p>There is a newer version of Textpattern CMS available. To take advantage of the latest features and security, it is recommended you upgrade.</p>
<p>Please note that while we strive to make the upgrade experience as seamless and pain-free as possible:</p>
<ul>
    <li>If only the last digit differs from your current version, the upgrade is likely to be backwards compatible with plugins and themes.</li>
    <li>If the last two digits differ from your current version, the upgrade might require updates to some plugins and/or themes, although it will probably continue to work anyway in a limited capacity.</li>
    <li>If the first digit is different from your current version, the upgrade is likely to require updates to most plugins and themes. If you rely heavily on a particular plugin or theme feature, please check with the author or community members before commencing the upgrade.</li>
</ul>
<p>If the messages reads “There is a problem trying to connect to the RPC server” it means a new version could not be checked at this time, or the server may be down. Updates are checked for every 24 hours so it is likely that next time you visit the Diagnostics panel, all will be well.</p></string>
  <string name="tmp_plugin_paths_match"><h2>Diagnostics: Temporary directory path and Plugin cache directory path should not match</h2>
<p>Plugins should have their own directory and not share the temporary directory. This is a potential security risk and may adversely affect your site if the temporary directory is flushed. Please ensure that the temporary directory path is different to the plugin cache path.</p></string>
  <string name="update_still_exists"><h2>Diagnostics: \'update\' directory still exists</h2>
<p>When Textpattern has been upgraded, the <code>textpattern/update</code> directory and its contents are no longer needed and recommended for deletion. You will continue to receive this warning until it has been removed.</p></string>
  <string name="warn_mail_unavailable"><h2>Diagnostics: Your PHP installation is missing the mail() function</h2>
<p>PHP’s <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/function.mail.php">mail <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> function is disabled. Therefore, Textpattern cannot send emails and some functionality will not be available. For example, email notifications for new comments will not be sent, and new users will not receive a welcome email. Users can still be added, however.</p></string>
  <string name="warn_register_globals_or_update"><h2>Diagnostics: Turn register_globals off or update to a newer PHP version</h2>
<p>A severe vulnerability was discovered in certain versions of PHP concerning the controversial legacy feature <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="https://secure.php.net/manual/en/security.globals.php">registered globals <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a>. This can lead to unexpected behaviour of PHP applications, which can potentially allow execution of remote PHP code in many situations.</p>
<p>Vulnerable versions are PHP4 versions &lt;= 4.4.0 and PHP5 versions &lt;= 5.0.5. You should either update to a newer version or make sure that <code>register_globals</code> is turned off. <code>register_globals</code> was deprecated as of PHP 5.3.0 and removed as of PHP 5.4.0.</p>
<p>You can turn off <code>register_globals</code> in the <code>php.ini</code> file. If you are in a hosted environment, you may have an option in your hosting control panel for it (ask your host). When running PHP as an Apache module, it is also possible to turn <code>register_globals</code> off via Apache’s <code>.htaccess</code> configuration files. Uncomment the following line from your <code>.htaccess</code> file by removing the leading #:</p>
<pre><code>php_value register_globals 0</code></pre></string>
</resources>
