<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Generated by crowdin.com-->
<resources>
  <string name="about_privileges"><h1>Käyttäjät: Tietoa rooleista</h1>
<h3>Julkaisija</h3>
<ul>
    <li>voi hallita artikkeleita, kommentteja ja linkkejä</li>
    <li>voi käyttää PHP: ta artikkeleissa jos hallintapaneelin asetus ‘Salli PHP artikkeleissa?’ on ‘Kyllä’</li>
    <li>voi hallita kuvia ja tiedostoja</li>
    <li>voi hallita osioita ja kategorioita</li>
    <li>voi hallita sivuja, lomakkeita ja tyylejä</li>
    <li>voi tarkastella diagnostiikkatietoja</li>
    <li>voi hallita sivuston asetuksia</li>
    <li>voi hallita käyttäjätilejä</li>
    <li>voi hallita lokitietoja sivuston vierailijoista</li>
    <li>voi hallita liitännäisiä</li>
    <li>voi tuoda tietoja</li>
</ul>
<h3>Vastaava toimittaja</h3>
<ul>
    <li>voi hallita artikkeleita, kommentteja ja linkkejä</li>
    <li>voi käyttää PHP: ta artikkeleissa jos hallintapaneelin asetus ‘Salli PHP artikkeleissa?’ on ‘Kyllä’</li>
    <li>voi hallita kuvia ja tiedostoja</li>
    <li>voi hallita osioita ja kategorioita</li>
    <li>voi hallita sivuja, lomakkeita ja tyylejä</li>
    <li>voi tarkastella diagnostiikkatietoja</li>
    <li>voi hallita sivuston asetuksia</li>
    <li>voi tarkastella käyttäjätilejä</li>
    <li>voi hallita lokitietoja sivuston vierailijoista</li>
    <li>voi hallita liitännäisiä</li>
    <li>voi tuoda tietoja</li>
</ul>
<h3>Tekstin toimittaja</h3>
<ul>
    <li>voi hallita artikkeleita seuraavan rajoituksen ulkopuolella:
        <ul>
            <li>ei voi poistaa artikkeleita, jotka kuuluvat muille käyttäjille</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>voi hallita kommentteja ja linkkejä</li>
    <li>voi hallita kuvia ja tiedostoja</li>
    <li>voi hallita kategorioita</li>
    <li>voi hallita sivuja ja lomakkeita</li>
    <li>voi tarkastella käyttäjätilejä</li>
    <li>voi hallita lokitietoja sivuston vierailijoista</li>
</ul>
<h3>Rivitoimittaja</h3>
<ul>
    <li>voi hallita omia artikkeleita, voi tarkastella muiden käyttäjien artikkeleita</li>
    <li>voi hallita kuvia ja tiedostoja</li>
</ul>
<h3>Vapaa toimittaja</h3>
<ul>
    <li>voi hallita omia artikkeleita seuraavin rajoituksin:
        <ul>
            <li>voi muokata artikkelia kunnes se on julkaistu</li>
            <li>voi muuttaa statusta <em>vain</em> jos se on Luonnos, Piilotettu tai Odottaa hyväksyntää</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>voi katsella muiden käyttäjien artikkeleita</li>
</ul>
<h3>Suunnittelija</h3>
<ul>
    <li>voi hallita omia artikkeleita seuraavin rajoituksin:
        <ul>
            <li>voi muokata artikkelia kunnes se on julkaistu</li>
            <li>voi muuttaa statusta <em>vain</em> jos se on Luonnos, Piilotettu tai Odottaa hyväksyntää</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>voi tarkastella muiden käyttäjien artikkeleita</li>
    <li>voi hallita kuvia</li>
    <li>voi hallita osioita</li>
    <li>voi hallita sivuja, lomakkeita ja tyylejä</li>
</ul></string>
  <string name="add_new_author"><h1>Käyttäjät: Luo uusi tekijä</h1>
<p>Salasana, tervetuloviesti ja ohjeet kirjautumista varten lähetetään tekijälle sähköpostitse.</p></string>
  <string name="admin_side_plugins"><h1>Asetukset: Käytetäänkö ylläpito-osion liitännäisiä?</h1>
<p>Ylläpito-osion liitännäiset voivat muuttaa hallintapaneelin käyttöliittymän toimintatapaa. Liitännäiset voivat myös vaikuttaa olemassa oleviin toiminnallisuuksiin, kuten artikkelien muokkaamiseen tai julkaisemiseen, ja ne voivat myös lisätä uusia elementtejä ulkoasuun uusien/laajennettujen toiminnallisuuksien tarjoamiseksi.</p>
<p>Mikäli haluat oppia lisää ylläpito-osion liitännäisistä, ole hyvä ja tutustu <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/development/">Extending Textpattern</a> -sivuun <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/">Textpatternin Käyttäjädokumentaatiossa</a>. Liitännäisiä on luetteloitu <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://textpattern.org/">Textpattern Resources</a> -sivustolla.</p></string>
  <string name="remember_login"><h2>Remember login</h2>
<p>When checked, you will remain logged in to your Textpattern account with the current web browser, until you choose to log out. If left unchecked, you will be automatically logged out after a period of inactivity.</p>
<p>Requires cookies to be enabled in your browser.</p></string>
  <string name="article_image"><h2>Write: Article image</h2>
<p>If you would like to associate a single image with this article, place one of the following here:</p>
<ol>
    <li>a Textpattern image ID</li>
    <li>a relative URL to the image (e.g. <code>/images/my_pic.jpg</code>)</li>
    <li>a fully-qualified URL (e.g. <code>http://example.com/path/to/images/my_pic.jpg</code>)</li>
</ol>
<p>The image can be displayed by placing a <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/article_image"><code>&lt;txp:article_image /&gt;</code> tag <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> inside an article form. It will output a complete HTML <code>&lt;img&gt;</code> tag to your chosen image.</p></string>
  <string name="body"><h2>Write: Body</h2>
<p>The main content of an article is contained within the article body.</p>
<p>When composing or preparing articles for publication in Textpattern, you can switch between three views of the article: plain text, HTML markup (the code with which a web browser renders the article), and a rendered preview.</p></string>
  <string name="description"><h2>Write: Description</h2>
<p>The article description is an optional component that can help search engines and website crawlers better identify and sort content.</p>
<p>The article description is limited to a maximum of 255 characters. Note that some search engines place character limits on the length of a page’s <code>meta description</code> for practicality of display in search engine results pages (SERPs) and this may be less than the 255 character limit in Textpattern.</p>
<p>Note that the article description differs from the article excerpt, though they both accept similar content. The article description should be primarily intended for use with search engines and crawlers, whereas the the article excerpt is more suited for a human-readable article summary where desired.</p></string>
  <string name="excerpt"><h2>Write: Excerpt</h2>
<p>Article excerpts are optional. Excerpts could be used as a short summary of the article that is displayed as part of a table of contents, used in place of the full article body in the site’s RSS/Atom feeds, or a number of other uses.</p></string>
  <string name="expire_date"><h2>Write: Expire date</h2>
<p>The time an article is labelled as expired. The time is optional and can be set to an arbitrary time in the past or future.</p>
<p>The boxes correspond to the following information:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Year / Month / Day</li>
    <li>Hour (24-hour format) : Minute : Second</li>
</ul>
<p>When the time arrives, or in the case where a time in the past is provided, the article expires.</p>
<p>If the option to display expired articles is enabled, the article remains visible. If the option to display expired articles is disabled, visitors to the article page will be served an HTTP 410 error in place of the article content.</p></string>
  <string name="keywords"><h2>Write: Keywords</h2>
<p>Keywords are useful for refining the relationships between articles beyond those provided by categories.</p>
<p>Keywords must be individual words separated by commas.</p></string>
  <string name="override_form"><h2>Write: Override form</h2>
<p>If you wish for an article to use a form different from that assigned by default - for example if you want to show only an article excerpt with <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/excerpt"><code>&lt;txp:excerpt /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> where you normally show the entire article with <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/body"><code>&lt;txp:body /&gt;</code> <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> - this can be set here.</p></string>
  <string name="publish_date"><h2>Write: Publish date</h2>
<p>The time an article or file is published or most-recently revised. The time can be set to the moment the item is published, or to an arbitrary time in the past or future.</p>
<p>The boxes correspond to the following information:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Year / Month / Day</li>
    <li>Hour (24-hour format) : Minute : Second</li>
</ul>
<p>An item with a timestamp greater than the current time (i.e. in the future) will not appear on the front end and the RSS/Atom feeds until that time arrives.</p></string>
  <string name="title"><h2>Write: Title</h2>
<p>Add an appropriate title for this article.</p>
<p>An article title is limited to a maximum of 255 characters.</p></string>
  <string name="url_title"><h2>Write: URL-only title</h2>
<p>If you would like to have a specific title attached to the permalink URL for your article, enter it here. If it is left blank, the URL title will be automatically generated from the article title.</p>
<p>This is particularly useful if the title of your article uses non-ASCII characters.</p></string>
  <string name="allow_article_php_scripting"><h2>Preferences: Allow PHP in articles?</h2>
<p>When enabled, this setting will allow use of PHP within articles. The author must have sufficient privileges to do so (by default, only <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/administration/user-roles-and-privileges">‘Publishers’ <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> and <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/administration/user-roles-and-privileges">‘Managing Editors’ <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a> can).</p>
<p>PHP code must have opening and closing PHP tags omitted, and also be enclosed within <a rel="external" target="_blank" href="http://docs.textpattern.io/tags/php"><code>&lt;txp:php&gt;</code> tags <span class="ui-icon ui-icon-extlink">(opens an external link in a new window)</span></a>.</p></string>
</resources>
